# **Nick Staggs**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickstaggs

904-899-3207 https://github.com/nickstaggs nick.c.staggs@gmail.com

## Summary

I am a junior level software engineer who loves to be challenged every day; I am constantly pushing myself in and out of work to learn the art and intricacies of programming. I aim to write the most orthogonal, readable, and extensible code in order for a project to be easily maintainable and scalable for years to come. I am currently trying to switch over from Java enterprise development to web development and have worked hard outside of work to learn the latest web technologies, such as AngularJS, as well as the best practices associated with them

### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: Java(EE 7), C, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript(JQuery, Angular 1.x, NodeJS)

Database Systems: Oracle, MySQL, MongoDB

**Development Tools:** Git, SVN, Atom IDE, Eclipse IDE

## Work Experience

## **Guidewell Source (Under Contract to)**

Jacksonville, FL

IT Associate Developer

October 2016-Present

- Architected and implemented multithreaded file transfer service
- Developed in Java using Eclipse
- Implemented using the test driven development methodology with JUnit

**Orange County ISS** 

Orlando, FL

Intern

April 2014 – December 2015

• Developed complex and diverse SQL queries for business operations

Homeward Residential

Jacksonville, FL

**Quality Assurance Intern** 

May 2012 – August 2012

• Created detailed presentation on the internship's effectiveness and recommendations for quality assurance process improvement, which I presented to senior management

# **Projects**

#### **3D Virtual Piano**

Processes for Object Oriented Software Development

- Coded in Java using Eclipse IDE and the iMonkeyEngine
- Developed using Scrum, an Agile software development methodology
- User could play ten keys on 3D rendered piano

#### Education

**University of Central Florida** – Orlando, FL

May 2016

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 2.91

### **Relevant Courses**

Processes in OO Software Development • Algorithms • Statistics for Engineers • Database Systems